

+254740938029 mainalawrence32@gmail.com 19, Karatina, Nyeri 10101 Kenya

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Talented Full-stack web and software developer with 4+ years of coding experience and expertise in project planning. Successfully monitors and controls all phases of the development process, design, construction, and testing. Works collaboratively within multifunctional teams to identify and resolve bugs and functionality issues. Strong technical

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer, Fiverr, Mar 2018 - Current, Remote

Other than a Strong understanding of the web development cycle, programming techniques, and tools.

I have Collaborated with the front-end, and back-end developers and other team members to establish objectives and design more functional, cohesive codes to enhance the user experience. more to that, I have gained Strong problem-solving and verbal and written communication skills over the years.

Backend Developer, Digital Servers Center, Dec 2022 - Jan 2023, Remote Saudi Arabia

- Wrote clean code to develop functional web applications.
- · Managed cutting-edge technologies to improve legacy applications.
- · Devised and implemented robust data protection and security measures.
- · Resolved client technical issues through debugging and research.
- Documented style guidelines to keep the design consistent across the team.
- Produced code in programming languages such as Typescript and Javascript to create the most effective and clean websites.
- Wrote unit tests for the Developed Apis

Full Stack Web Developer Intern, the Jitu, Jan 2022 - Mar 2022, Nyeri Kenya

The following was what I took from the Internship:

- 1) Write code and tests, build prototypes and resolve issues.
- 2) Design robust APIs to support mobile and desktop clients.
- 3) Manage and optimize scalable distributed systems in the cloud.
- 4)Optimize web applications for performance and scalability.
- 5) Maintain and improve the website.
- 6) Collaborate with other developers to improve usability.
- 7) Ensure high-quality graphic standards and brand consistency

Software Development Coach, TAISA, Mar 2020 - Jan 2021, Nyeri

Designed a curriculum and co-authored a technical book for training on Game Development.I mentored and trained High School students to design and create games, animations, and simple educative applications

SKILLS

- Javascript
- Qt C++ Qml
- SQL
- React
- Node
- Teamwork
- · Public speaking

- Typescript
- Docker
- Docker
- Angular
- Problem-solving
- Planning

EDUCATION

Diploma of Information Communication Technology, Computer and Information Sciences

NYERI NATIONAL POLYTECHNIC - Nyeri, Kenya

Mar 2022

Back in college, I would do well in almost everything concerning computer programming, networking, software design, and everything else related to coding since from an early age I was passionate about computers.

High School Diploma, High School studies

Dec 2016

Kangocho Secondary School - Karatina, Nyeri,

LANGUAGES

English, Fluent

Swahili, Native